export const SOCIALSTUDIESA2011 = [

{
id: "question1",
question: "1. The liberty of the individual in the Ghanaian society can be curtailed when one",
A: "speaks one’s mind",
B: "refuses to vote",
C: "joins the opposition party",
D: "deserts national service",
answer: "D. deserts national service",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question2",
question: "2. The extended family system in the Ghanaian society has been undermined by",
A: "formal education",
B: "lack of educational facilities",
C: "rural-urban migration",
D: "influx of foreigners",
answer: "C. rural-urban migration",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question3",
question: "3. The bringing together of all individuals in a nation, based on common cultural trait is termed national",
A: "allegiance",
B: "identity",
C: "co-operation",
D: "pledge",
answer: "B. identity",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question4",
question: "4. The best way to ensure proper handling of currency notes is",
A: "encouraging more savings",
B: "providing wallets to workers",
C: "intensifying public education",
D: "printing of more currency notes",
answer: "C. intensifying public education",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question5",
question: "5. A society is said to be dynamic when its culture",
A: "undergoes constant change",
B: "varies from others",
C: "is preserved",
D: "is homogenous",
answer: "A. undergoes constant change",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question6",
question: "6. A leader and a follower are inseparable because",
A: "both are partners in the development process",
B: "they belong to the same religion",
C: "they have the same-level of education",
D: "they have the same ethnic background",
answer: "A. both are partners in the development process",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question7",
question: "7. The greatest employer of labour in Ghana is the",
A: "telecommunication industry",
B: "banking industry",
C: "public enterprise",
D: "construction industry",
answer: "C. public enterprise",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question8",
question: "8. The process of production is said to be complete when the goods",
A: "reach the warehouse",
B: "reach the final consumer",
C: "have been packaged",
D: "are ready for distribution",
answer: "B. reach the final consumer",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question9",
question: "9. Which following is not a cultural value of Ghana?",
A: "Celibacy",
B: "Tolerance",
C: "Modesty",
D: "Sympathy",
answer: "A. Celibacy",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question10",
question: "10. One result of a breakdown in constitutional rule is that it leads to",
A: "illiteracy",
B: "depletion of natural resources",
C: "decrease in mining activities",
D: "insecurity.",
answer: "D. insecurity",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question11",
question: "11. A common feature of the extended family system in Ghana is",
A: "high level of integrity",
B: "security for all members",
C: "prosperity for all",
D: "formal education for all",
answer: "B. security for all members",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question12",
question: "12. One of the objectives of the New Partnership for Africa’s Development (NEPAD) initiative is to",
A: "eradicate all forms of colonialism from Africa",
B: "accelerate the empowerment of women",
C: "promote peace in Africa",
D: "remove all trade barriers",
answer: "B. accelerate the empowerment of women",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question13",
question: "13. The organ charged with the administration of the African Union (Å U) is the",
A: "Commission",
B: "Assembly",
C: "Executive Council",
D: "Pan African Parliament",
answer: "C. Executive Council",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question14",
question: "14. Which of the following is true about autocratic leadership?",
A: "Sharing of responsibilities with followers",
B: "Ability to carry people along",
C: "Encouragement of divide and rule",
D: "Readiness to take quick decisions",
answer: "D. Readiness to take quick decisions",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question15",
question: "15. The most important agency of primary socialization is the",
A: "community",
B: "school",
C: "media",
D: "home",
answer: "D. home",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question16",
question: "16. The arrangement whereby newly married couples establish their own household helps",
A: "prevent divorce",
B: "limit in-law interference",
C: "promote unending love",
D: "prevent domestic violence",
answer: "B. limit in-law interference",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question17",
question: "17. Which of the following cannot promote sustained growth and development in Ghana?",
A: "Reliance on foreign aid",
B: "Good quality resources",
C: "Maintenance culture",
D: "Education and Training",
answer: "A. Reliance on foreign aid",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question18",
question: "18. A rapid population growth in a country",
A: "reduces the size of the older group",
B: "reduces the size of the working group",
C: "expands the size of the young group",
D: "expands the size of the older group",
answer: "C. expands the size of the young group",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question19",
question: "19. A citizen can play a key role in nation building by",
A: "being a member of a political party",
B: "constructively criticising the policies of the government",
C: "being a member of a voluntary organization",
D: "making donations to religious bodies",
answer: "B. constructively criticising the policies of the government",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question20",
question: "20. In order to fully exploit her natural resources, Ghana needs to",
A: "train more skilled manpower",
B: "expand her foreign trade",
C: "reduce the rate of population growth",
D: "employ more foreign administrators",
answer: "A. train more skilled manpower",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question21",
question: "21. Underpopulation occurs when a country’s population is",
A: "made up mostly of people under eighteen years",
B: "declining at a fast rate",
C: "less than the available resources",
D: "more than the available resources",
answer: "C. less than the available resources",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question22",
question: "22. Which of the following performs a parenthood rule?",
A: "A woman who works in a nursery",
B: "A woman who has her own child",
C: "A couple who adopts a child",
D: "An older sibling who takes care of a younger one",
answer: "B. A woman who has her own child",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question23",
question: "23. In the Ghanaian traditional society, a family is defined as a set of people",
A: "who practice the same religion",
B: "who speak the same language",
C: "living in the same community",
D: "who are related by blood",
answer: "D. who are related by blood",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question24",
question: "24. The values and customs passed on to a people from their ancestors are referred to as",
A: "heritage",
B: "taboos",
C: "folklore",
D: "lineage",
answer: "A. heritage",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question25",
question: "25. The privileges conferred by law and nature on an individual because of his/her membership in a community are regarded as",
A: "inheritance",
B: "rights",
C: "honours",
D: "reward",
answer: "B. rights",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question26",
question: "26. The ultimate goal of Maslow’s theory of needs is the",
A: "desire for self-actualization",
B: "need for security",
C: "need to satisfy hunger ang shelter",
D: "need for self-esteem",
answer: "A. desire for self-actualization",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question27",
question: "27. The process or parenthood stops only when",
A: "parents give out their children in marriage",
B: "parents are no longer alive",
C: "children start to work",
D: "children complete their education",
answer: "B. parents are no longer alive",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question28",
question: "28. Environmental protection involves",
A: "giving farmers extension services",
B: "keeping animals in the zoo",
C: "controlling the destructive activities of man",
D: "controlling population growth",
answer: "B. keeping animals in tile zoo",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question29",
question: "29. The role of an individual in a community includes all the following except",
A: "volunteering information",
B: "taking part in communal Iabour",
C: "voting at elections",
D: "collection of taxes",
answer: "D. collection of taxes",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question30",
question: "30. A book containing all cash and bank transactions of a business enterprise is called",
A: "Bank Statement",
B: "Purchase Day Book",
C: "Sale Day Book",
D: "Cashbook",
answer: "D. Cashbook",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question31",
question: "31. When two countries decide to work together on economic political and social basis to enhance progress and development, they are promoting",
A: "bilateral co-operation",
B: "economic co-operation",
C: "international co-operation",
D: "multi-lateral co-operation",
answer: "A. bilateral co-operation",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question32",
question: "32. In a limited liability company risks are borne by the",
A: "shareholders",
B: "partners",
C: "government",
D: "directors",
answer: "A. shareholders",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question33",
question: "33. To ensure efficient use of human resource in Ghana, the government should",
A: "appoint only members of the ruling party to key positions",
B: "appoint only qualified people to occupy key position",
C: "redeploy more civil servants to the rural areas",
D: "pay higher wages and salaries",
answer: "B. appoint only qualified people to occupy key positions",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question34",
question: "34. One advantage of an adolescent girl abstaining from pre-marital sex is",
A: "getting a better marriage partner",
B: "protections from unwanted pregnancy",
C: "giving birth to intelligent children",
D: "getting better employment",
answer: "B. protections from unwanted pregnancy",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question35",
question: "35. A body of knowledge about our physical world acquired through enquiry and mental effort is",
A: "technology",
B: "invention",
C: "innovation",
D: "science",
answer: "D. science",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question36",
question: "36. A youthful population with a high fertility rate implies",
A: "high employment rate",
B: "low cost of living",
C: "better understanding of family planning methods",
D: "high dependency burden",
answer: "D. high dependency burden",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question37",
question: "37. A characteristic of a traditional government is that",
A: "there is no organized opposition",
B: "there is no consensus building",
C: "the chief is a dictator",
D: "the chief serves for a definite period",
answer: "A. there is no organized opposition",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question38",
question: "38. A leader who capitalizes on old age to determine policies and procedures for the group is",
A: "democratic",
B: "paternalistic",
C: "charismatic",
D: "autocratic",
answer: "B. paternalistic",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question39",
question: "39. To be enstooled as a chief in the traditional Ghanaian society the candidate must",
A: "possess a strong physique",
B: "be affiliated to the ruling party",
C: "have a good character",
D: "be generous to people",
answer: "C. have a good character",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question40",
question: "40. To meet the man power needs of the Ghanaian society",
A: "salaries of workers must be increased",
B: "the government must invite more foreign workers.",
C: "educational goals must be geared towards acquisition of skills",
D: "adequate incentives should be given to workers",
answer: "C. educational goals must be geared towards acquisition of skills",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question41",
question: "41. Open political competition is commonly associated with a system of government known as",
A: "oligarchy",
B: "monarchy",
C: "democracy",
D: "communism",
answer: "D. communism",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question42",
question: "42. Which of the following does constitute social development",
A: "Protecting visitors",
B: "Setting up industries",
C: "Being sensitive to societal norms",
D: "Better attitudes towards one another",
answer: "B. Setting up industries",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question43",
question: "43. In which of the following sectors would you place an individual employed to serve customers in a bank?",
A: "Primary",
B: "Tertiary",
C: "Secondary",
D: "Extractive",
answer: "C. Secondary",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question44",
question: "44. The classification of marriage by residence whereby the couples live separately in their homes is",
A: "neolocal",
B: "duolocal",
C: "patrilocal",
D: "matrilocal",
answer: "B. duolocal",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question45",
question: "45. Partnership is more preferred to sole proprietorship in Ghana because",
A: "there is spread of risk",
B: "it encourages quick",
C: "it is easy to form",
D: "there is absence of conflict",
answer: "A. there is spread of risk",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question46",
question: "46. A major benefit Ghana derives from trading with other countries is",
A: "improvement in foreign relations",
B: "getting aid for disaster victims.",
C: "selling goods which she is unable to produce",
D: "creating employment avenues for her people",
answer: "C. selling goods which she is unable to produce",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question47",
question: "47. A business enterprise can best be sustained by",
A: "producing high quality goods at affordable prices",
B: "producing more goods and services",
C: "often changing prices of goods",
D: "employing more workers in the industrial sector",
answer: "A. producing high quality goods at affordable prices",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question48",
question: "48. Which of the following best explains the term technology?",
A: "Knowledge acquired through the use of computers",
B: "The use of sophisticated machinery to produce weapons of war",
C: "The use of scientific knowledge to satisfy human needs",
D: "The knowledge acquired through systematic enquiry",
answer: "C. The use of scientific knowledge to satisfy human needs",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question49",
question: "49. One procedure for the settlement of labour disputes is through",
A: "confrontation",
B: "arbitration",
C: "agitation",
D: "intimidation",
answer: "B. arbitration",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question50",
question: "50. Primary production involves",
A: "extraction of goods from natural resources",
B: "distribution of goods to consumers",
C: "rendering of services to people",
D: "the use of machines to add value to goods",
answer: "A. extraction of goods from natural resources",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},



]